http://goulds.com/mappolicy/

Xylem Brands
Xylem Watermark
Careers
Let’s Solve Water
Country/LanguageSelect your country or regionAmericasCanadaMexicoUnited StatesEuropeAustriaFranceGermanyIrelandItalyLowara - InternationalLowara - SpainNetherlandsPolandPortugalRussiaUnited KingdomAsia/OceaniaAsia RegionAustraliaChinaHong KongIndonesiaKoreaMalaysiaSingaporeThailandVietnamMiddle East/AfricaMiddle East Region
Request Info
Home Owner Support
Navigation
Products
Centrifugal Pumps & Boosters
Commercial Pool & Water Park Pumps
Multi-Stage Pumps
Self-Priming End Suction
AquaBoost Advanced Packaged Booster System
AquaBoost Variable Speed Booster Package (Obsolete)
AquaForce e-HV
AquaForce e-MT
AquaForce XL (Obsolete)
Aquavar e-ABII
AquaForce Variable Speed Pump Station (Obsolete-Replaced by AquaForce e-MT)
Jet Pumps
Convertible Jet Pumps
Deep Well Jet Pumps
Jet Pump & Tank Packages
Shallow Well Jet Pumps
ProPak Kits
Submersible Well Pump Motors
4 Inch Well Pump Motors
AqWiFi – Remote Monitoring Device
Aquavar SOLO (OBSOLETE)
Aquavar SPD
Hydrovar – 5th Generation
Hydrovar – 4th Generation (OBSOLETE)
Wastewater & Drainage Pumps
Effluent Pumps
Grinder Pumps
Sewage Pumps
Specialty Pumps
Sump Pumps
Wastewater Packages
Red Jacket Series
Red Jacket Series Jets
Red Jacket Series Submersibles
Red Jacket Series Wastewater
Quick LinksHome Owner Web SiteRed Jacket SeriesHistorical ArchiveU.S. Department of Energy Efficiency Standards (DOE)
Literature Library
Training & Education
Training Overview
e-Learning
Factory School
ON-DEMAND TRAINING VIDEOS
Podcast Series
Webinar Trainings
Loaner Program
U.S. Department of Energy Efficiency Standards (DOE)
Sales & Service
Industrial Distributor Locator
Residential/Agriculture Distributor Locator
Home Owner Support
Consumer Online Purchase Policy
Minimum Advertised Price (MAP) Policy
Marlow Series Commercial Pool Pump Distributors
Red Jacket Series Sales & Service
Attachments located in downloadable pdf
The following is a restatement of our MAP Policy followed by the revised version now in effect to increase the success of full compliance by all our channel partners.
1. Minimum Advertised Price (MAP) Policy
Restatement:
1. Each Goulds Professional Dealer Association (“GPDA”) member is free to independently decide whether or not to follow the MAP Policy. However, XYLEM may in its sole discretion remove any or all of the benefits provided to GPDA Members in the event of non-compliance with our MAP Policy.
2. We have included a MAP pricing schedule; see Attachment 1 for your reference. Xylem reserves the right to modify the MAP pricing schedule at any time.
3. Xylem does not regulate pricing – Distributor is free to sell at whatever price it chooses.
4. Violating our MAP Policy will result in graduated enforcement by loss of access to buying programs, special payment terms, discounts, rebates, promotional marketing programs.
5. Failure to comply can ultimately result in termination.
2.  Revised MAP Policy
The following revised MAP policy, effective immediately, supersedes and replaces the current MAP Policy (with the following revised MAP policy referred to as “MAP Policy”):
1. Xylem does not regulate your sales pricing – distributors and all resellers are free to sell into the market at whatever price they choose.
2. Xylem maintains a minimum advertised price policy (“MAP Policy”) respective to Goulds Water Technology branded products to create an even playing field for all distributors and resellers and to help support brand equity
3. Xylem makes certain benefits available to its distributor and GPDA members, such as access to buying programs, special payment terms, discounts, rebates, and promotional marketing programs (collectively “Benefits”). At the end of each calendar year, Xylem will review each distributor’s and GPDA member’s compliance with the MAP Policy as well as any Benefits each distributor and GPDA member have notionally accrued for the given year.  To the extent the distributor or GPDA member was in strict compliance with the MAP Policy for the entire year, any notionally accrued Benefits for the given year will vest in the distributor’s or GPDA member’s account with Xylem.  Anyone involved, either directly or indirectly, in any violation of the MAP Policy is subject to XYLEM, in its sole discretion, taking the following actions:
a. For distributors: graduated enforcement, including permanent forfeiture of all notionally accrued Benefits, eventual agreement termination, and available legal recourse.
b. For GPDA dealers and other resellers: enforcement, including permanent forfeiture of all notionally accrued Benefits and available legal recourse.
c. Loss of warranty-related credits and support.
4. MAP Policy violation enforcement action will extend to everyone involved, either directly or indirectly, in each violation.
5. Attachment 1, for your reference, contains a MAP pricing schedule. Xylem reserves the right to modify the MAP Policy pricing schedule at any time.
6. Xylem’s MAP Policy implementation and enforcement measures include:
a. MAP Policy compliance obligation hard-coded into all distribution agreements.
b. A new MAP Policy Violation Tracking Forum accessible to all members. Violations and Violators will be listed with 30 day grace period notifications for rectification.
c. An updated GPDA membership policy that includes MAP Policy compliance requirements.
d. Distributor requirement to ensure sales of Goulds Water Technology branded products include an express written requirement that their customers comply with the MAP Policy.
e. Use one of the below statements on distributor’s invoice documents:
The sale of Goulds Water Technology (GWT) equipment is conditioned on purchaser’s agreement to comply with GWT’s Minimum Advertised Price Policy (www.goulds.com/mappolicy) in any resale of the GWT equipment.
OR
The sale of the items on this invoice is conditioned on purchaser’s agreement to comply with all applicable manufacturer Minimum Advertised Price policies, which can be found here (distributor MAP Policies), in any resale of any of these items.
f.  Updated Xylem tracking and enforcement tools and protocols for efficient and impactful MAP Policy compliance.
Note: We will not provide any support, including warranty services, for products sold in violation of our MAP Policy. This Policy will be added to our Warranty – Consumer and Commercial.
Attachments located in downloadable pdf
Find Documents
Literature-Library
Resources & Tools
Selection Tools
Training
Connect With Us
News & Updates
Case Studies
About Xylem
Xylem Watermark
Xylem Inc.
Policies
Privacy Policy
Terms & Conditions
Transparency in Supply Chains
Follow Us
Facebook
Twitter
LinkedIn
Copyright 2020 Xylem Inc. All rights reserved.
Xylem uses 'cookies' and 'media beacons'. For more information, visit our Privacy Policy page
Privacy Policy Acceptance
Necessary Preference Cookies
Peformance Cookies
Marketing Cookies
Why am I seeing this?
Privacy Policy Acceptance
We are committed to ensuring that the individuals whose details we hold understand our privacy practices. In particular, we want to make sure that we are respectful of your data protection preferences, and that you understand your data privacy rights.
By providing personal data to Xylem, you acknowledge that you have read and understand the terms of our Website Privacy Statement.
You can adjust all of your cookie settings by navigating the tabs on the left.
Necessary Preference Cookies
Necessary Preference cookies help make our website usable by enabling basic functions like page navigation. The website cannot function properly without these cookies. This type of cookie should be enabled at all times so that we can save your preferences for all other cookie settings.
Preference cookies enable the website to remember information that changes the way the website behaves or looks, like your preferred language or the region that you are in. No other personal information is collected.
If you disable this cookie, we will not be able to save your preferences. This means that every time you visit this website you will need to enable or disable cookies again.
Marketing Cookies
This website may use the following additional cookies, your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing the relevant features:
Twitter Widget shows the Xylem brands twitter stream and has a feature for like and retweet. Click here to learn more about how this cookie is managed by Twitter.
Facebook SDK shows the Xylem brand timeline and allow visitors to like the fb page and send message to fb page admin. Click here to learn more about how this cookie is managed by Facebook.
Please enable Necessary Preference Cookies first so that we can save your preferences!
Peformance Cookies
These cookies allow us to count visits and traffic sources, so we can measure and improve the performance of our site. They help us know which pages are the most and least popular and see how visitors move around the site.
All information these cookies collect is aggregated and therefore anonymous.
Please enable Necessary Preference Cookies first so that we can save your preferences!
Why am I seeing this?
This communication provides access to our Privacy Notice. It explains in clear language what information we collect about individuals, how we use it, and the choices and controls you have.
We have also recently updated our Privacy Notice to ensure that it meets high transparency requirements for data privacy in compliance with the EU data protection law known as the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), which went into effect on May 25, 2018.
Accept
Save Changes
